The first convolutional layer in a CNN applies a set of
CNN 中的第一个卷积层
image filters to an input image and outputs a stack of feature maps.
对输入图像应用一组图像过滤器并输出一组特征图
After such a network is trained,
训练完此类网络后
we can get a sense of what kinds of features this first layer has learned to
我们可以通过可视化每个过滤器学习的权重
extract by visualizing the learned weights for each of these filters.
了解第一个层级学会提取的是什么样的特征
We know that filters are grids of weight values and so
我们知道过滤器是权重值网格
we can visualize them by treating them like a small image.
因此可以通过将它们当做小图来可视化它们
1 3 by three filter for a grayscale image can be
一个 3x3 灰度图像过滤器
pictured as a three-by-three grayscale pixel image,
可以看做一个 3x3 灰度像素图像
where each pixel contains a learned weight value.
每个像素包含学习的权重值
The bright pixels can be thought of as positive or high values for weights.
亮的像素可以看做权重是正值或很高的值
The darker pixels correspond to small or negative weights.
暗的像素对应的是很小或负的权重
So, a kernel that looks like this with
因此像这样的卷积核
bright values on the top and dark values on the bottom,
在顶部是亮的像素值 在底部是暗的像素值
we might think that it subtracts bottom pixels from top pixels in a patch and so,
我们可能会认为它按区域从顶部像素中减去底部像素
it can detect horizontal edges in an image.
因此可以检测到图像中的水平边缘
For a CNN that analyzes color images,
对于分析彩色图像的 CNN
the filters just have another dimension for color,
过滤器具有另一个表示颜色的维度
and can be displayed as small color images.
可以显示为小的彩色图像
Here are some examples of filters from
这些是在具有 11x11 色彩过滤器的 CNN 的
the first convolutional layer of a CNN with 11 by 11 color filters.
第一个卷积层中应用的一些过滤器示例
You can see that a lot of these filters are
可以看出很多这种过滤器
looking for specific kinds of geometric patterns,
在寻找特定的几何图形
vertical or horizontal edges,
垂直或水平边缘用呈各种角度的
which are represented by alternating bars of light and dark at different angles.
浅色和深色替代长条表示
You can also see corner detectors and filters that appear to detect areas of
还可以看到角落检测器和检测具有对比颜色的区域过滤器
opposing colors with magenta and green bunches or blue and orange lines.
这些区域具有品红和绿色隆起或蓝色和橘色线条
Now you might be thinking great,
你可能会认为
this is really simple.
这很简单啊
I can just look at the filter weights of a trans CNN to see what my network is learning.
我可以直接查看训练的 CNN 的过滤器权重 看看网络学到了什么
But this becomes tricky as soon as you move further into
但是当你尝试进一步查看网络
the network and try to look at the second or even third convolutional layer.
并查看第二个或甚至第三个卷积层时 就会变得非常复杂
This is because these later layers are no longer directly connected to the input image.
因为这些后续层级不再与输入图像直接相关
They're connected to some output that has likely been
它们与某些可能被池化和
pooled and processed by an activation function.
由激活函数处理过的输出相关
So, visualizing the filters in these deeper layers doesn't
因此 可视化更深的层级中的过滤器
clearly tell us what these layers are actually seen in the original input image.
并不能清晰地表明这些层级真正从原始输入图像中看到的信息
So we'll need to develop a different technique to
我们需要开发一种不同的技巧
really see what's going on in these intermediate layers.
以便真正地查看这些中间层级发生的情况